Health is about cause and effect. Public health is about the cause of the cause.
I like many of you all have seen the video circulating of the doctor talking about the
dangers of hookah. I am in no way shape or form attempting to disagree with his deduction that
smoking hookah is bad for you. Now I will say I don't know nobody that said it was good for you
but maybe I'm just not talking to the right niggas. But I digress. My issue is not with the
physician in the slightest but rather when the conversation turns from I'm concerned with
people's health to everyone sending this to the city of Atlanta right now because hold the fuck
on. By every empirical study and metric statistic there is Atlanta is one of the most educated
fucking cities in America but that don't fit your narrative does it? Pause to read and pause to read.
Now education aside let's get to what's really happening. I brought up the causes of causes as
opposed to the causes of effects. What I'm essentially saying in all that cat and hat ass language is
let's talk about the societal factors. If you talk to niggas anywhere but specifically Atlanta about hookah
let's talk about the slave wages and the income inequality in this city. Let's talk about the
racist transit system that refused to expand that makes it so black folks in South Atlanta can't
get to the motherfucking good-paying jobs in the city or they have to run through the fucking hunger
games race to get there every goddamn day and the stress that that induces. Let's talk about that
first and when you address that and when you fix that then and only then can you fault motherfuckers for
relying on hookah at the end of the day. If I hadn't said it before I'm saying it now and I'll say that
shit again. Hating on Atlanta is hating on niggas. The metro Atlanta area has the highest density
population of niggas in the country to suggest that a take like this and sharing videos like
the shit that come from the shade room who have manipulated that doctor's message to be something
that it wasn't originally is fucking dangerous and we need to treat these things with so much
more care especially in the world we fucking living in bro.